forvo.com 2019-11-14

# Forvo Privacy Policy

## FULFILLMENT OF THE DUTY TO INFORM BY THE RESPONSIBLE APPLICATION CRITERIA AND LEGAL TEXTS.

### Privacy policy (1st layer)

**BASIC INFORMATION ON DATA PROTECTION**  
---  
Responsible | Forvo Media S.L. [\+ info](https://forvo.com/#responsible)  
Purpose | To manage and to administer the access to Forvo as well as sending information and/or newsletter [\+ info](https://forvo.com/#purpose)  
Legitimation | Consent of the interested party [\+ info](https://forvo.com/#legitimation)  
Recipients | There is no data transfer to third parties [\+ info](https://forvo.com/#recipients)  
Rights | To access, to rectify and to delete data, as well as other rights, as explained in the additional information [\+ info](https://forvo.com/#rights)  
Additional information | You can consult the additional and detailed information on Data Protection on our webpage:  
Privacy Policy: <https://forvo.com/privacy/>  
Legal Notice: <https://forvo.com/terms-and-conditions/>  
Cookies policy: <https://forvo.com/cookie-policy/>  
  
### Privacy policy (2nd layer)

In accordance with the Organic Law 15/1999, of December 13, Personal Data Protection (PDP), and the Regulation (EU) 2016/679, of the European Parliament and the Council, of April 27 ("General Data Protection Regulation" or "GDPR"), this Privacy Policy is applied to the processing of personal data that Forvo Media S.L. -hereinafter Forvo- performs **as Responsible** , in relation to the users' data (physical people) collected in any of the sections of the website.

If you do not agree with the terms of this Policy, do not access or use the Services. This Privacy Policy is not applicable to any other product, service or activity of third parties.

#### RESPONSIBLE FOR THE PROCESSING OF YOUR DATA

  * **Social Denomination: Forvo Media S.L.** , (Forvo)
  * **Address** : Txirrita Maleo 3G, 20100 Rentería, Gipuzkoa, Spain
  * **NIF** : B20987541
  * **Email** : [info@forvo.com](mailto:%20info@forvo.com)
  * **Registration data** : Volume: 2,408 - Page: 153Vto - Inscrip: 2nd - Section: 8th - Page: SS-31.114

#### WHAT PERSONAL DATA DOES FORVO PROCESS?

The personal data obtained by Forvo with the consent that you grant to us are the following:

  * Email address
  * User
  * Language
  * Gender
  * Location
  * Role
  * Information about the browser, operating system, and public IP
  * Where appropriate, pronunciations and comments made
  * Subscription to newsletters

#### WHAT PERSONAL DATA ARE MADE PUBLIC IN FORVO?

Forvo, as a pronunciation guide, publishes only the user data or alias that the registered person chooses.

#### PURPOSES OF DATA PROCESSING

Your personal data will be used for the generic purpose of the management and administration of the website, and specifically:

  * To **communicate with users** in response to requests, comments and questions that they might make through the contact forms on our website (including emails, phone calls, etc.)
  * For **Newsletters** : We can use your data to send our newsletter with news and our services or products, as well as third-party news where appropriate. This newsletter will be, in any case, **expressly authorized** by the user who can **revoke at any time** their consent to receive these notifications using the mechanism implemented to that end, or by sending a letter with the subject "Usubscribe" to [info@forvo.com](mailto:%20info@forvo.com).

We will not process your personal data for any other purpose beyond those described above, unless it is imposed by law or there is a judicial requirement.

#### DURATION OF DATA PROCESSING

Forvo will keep and process personal data from the moment the user gives their consent until they request, cancel or withdraw their consent for data processing.

If the subscription is cancelled, the pronunciations will be kept in accordance with the license of intellectual property of the website, although they are pseudo-anonymous, without including any personal data that could identify the author of the pronunciation.

**Possibility to withdraw the consent** : The user has the right to withdraw the consent at any time, without affecting the legality of the treatment based on the consent prior to its withdrawal. Likewise, the user may object at any time to the reception of any electronic communication from Forvo.

#### LEGITIMATION OF DATA PROCESSING

The legal basis for data processing is the legitimation based on the **consent of the interested party** for the purposes described above, which will be requested at the time of:

  * proceeding to treat your data
  * the inclusion of your data in our forms
  * signing up for our newsletter

The registration on the website and the requests for information that you send us require that the interested party voluntarily provide us with the necessary information to be able to assist them or provide them with the Services. The obligation or necessity of providing us with these data will be marked with an asterisk (*) in the forms or sections corresponding to each service.

However, the interested party can freely refuse to provide us with these data or, later, revoke the consent previously granted to process their data, although that refusal will imply our impossibility of being able to attend to their request or continue with the registration in our platform.

Likewise, we will be able to process your data based on the **legitimate interest** of Forvo to maintain and retain its users and better meet their previously expressed expectations or interests, e.g. improvement of services and products, management of requests, queries or claims, offer of products and similar services, information about promotions etc., without the prejudice to Forvo's compliance with the rest of the obligations related to sending commercial communications electronically.

Forvo understands that, by providing us with these data, the interested party guarantees and is responsible for the veracity, certainty and accuracy thereof and that they accept and consent expressly the processing of their data for the purposes described above.

#### RECIPIENTS OF ASSIGNMENTS OR TRANSFERS

With general character, Forvo will not transfer your personal data to third parties, unless we are legally bound to do so or you have expressly authorised us when using our services.

#### SOCIAL NETWORKS

Forvo has different social networks (Facebook, Twitter, etc.) to disseminate contents related to Forvo as well as to provide users with a way of contact. Forvo is responsible for the treatment of the data of its followers and contacts in social networks. Nevertheless, since the processing of personal data takes place within the framework of social networks whose suppliers impose operating rules, Forvo's obligations will be limited to those aspects in which the company is free to act. Under no circumstances will Forvo extract data from social networks, make profiles of its users or collect additional personal data related to tastes, hobbies or mode of use of social networks, without the express consent of those affected.

#### RIGHTS OF INTERESTED PEOPLE

Anyone has the right to obtain confirmation on whether or not their personal data is processed in Forvo. In particular, you can exercise the following rights before Forvo:

  * **Right of access** : it allows the interested party to know and obtain information about their personal data subject to processing.
  * **Right of rectification** : it allows to correct errors, to modify the data that prove to be inaccurate or incomplete and to guarantee the certainty of the information subject to processing.
  * **Right of suppression** : it allows to request the elimination of the data subject to processing when they are no longer necessary.
  * **Opposition right** : the right of the interested party not to carry out the processing of their personal data or to cease it, except for legitimate reasons or for the exercise or defence of possible claims, in which case we will keep them blocked during the corresponding term while the legal obligations persist.
  * **Right to oppose the sending of advertising** : those interested may oppose the sending of commercial communications by Forvo. In this case, you can revoke your consent at any time to receive these notifications using the mechanism implemented to that end, or by sending a letter with the subject "Unsubscribe" to [info@forvo.com](mailto:%20info@forvo.com).
  * **Limitation of the processing** : in certain circumstances, the interested parties may request the limitation of the processing of their data, in which case they will only be kept for the exercise or defence of claims.
  * **Portability of the data** : interested people can request to receive their concerning data that they have provided us or that we send them to another responsible of treatment of their choice –whenever it is technically possible–, in a structured format of common use and mechanical reading.
  * **The right not to be subject to automated individual decisions** (including the preparation of profiles): the right not to be the subject of a decision based on the automated treatment that produces significant effects.

**Possibility of withdrawing the consent** : Likewise, the interested party has the right to withdraw the consent given at any time, without affecting the legality of the processing based on the consent given at the time of providing us with their data.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights exposed, please send us a letter with all your information, including your ID to: Txirrita Maleo 3G, 20100 Rentería, Gipuzkoa, Spain or by email to [info@forvo.com](mailto:%20info@forvo.com).

You can also contact our Data Protection Delegate (DPD) through the following address or email: [info@forvo.com](mailto:%20info@forvo.com).

**Possibility of claiming before the Control Authority** : Forvo also informs you of the right that assists you to file a claim with the Spanish Agency for Data Protection ([www.agpd.es](https://www.agpd.es/)) if you consider that the processing does not comply with current regulations.
